

Top Flat, 174 Camden Road London NW1 9HJ

07779556191

contact@harveynick.com http://harveynick.com @harveynick

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickjohnson-6297711b

Profile

A PhD graduate and experienced developer with a very broad skill base. Equally adept at both creative and logical thinking, as well as trustworthy, intuitive, reliable and meticulous. I can claim to be an expert in Java and Objective-C, and very capable with C++, Swift, Python and Ruby. Any other language I need to do my job, I can learn.

I started learning to program at age 7 (seriously. On a ZX Spectrum +2A). I've been doing it, one way or another, ever since. At the end of the day I love to build things and solve problems. Programming is the most satisfying and immediate way I've found of doing both of those things. I think AI can be used to build truly great user experiences, and I want to be one of the ones building those experiences and using them to surprise, delight and inform.

Achievements

- Completely rebuilding the View and Edit UIs of Google Calendar iOS, to acclaim from both engineering and UX;
- Lobbying for the creation of AdSense for iPhone, learning Objective-C and iOS in order to build it, and launching the completed v1 App; all within two quarters;
- Completing my PhD on using narrative based user interfaces to effectively summarise complex missions and event series;
- Breaking an autonomous pipeline tracking world record whilst working offshore in Western Australia;
- Winning the Student Autonomous Underwater Competition Europe two years in a row, having worked on ever part of the vehicle from device drivers and hardware up to mission executive and user interface.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Google, London, UK - May 2014 - Present

I'm one of the lead developers on Google Calendar for iOS. Recently I rebuilt the entire View and Edit UI from the ground up (receiving Peer Bonuses from both Engineering and UX for this work). I've had input into every aspect of the UI, including writing all of the animations in the app. My work is not limited to the UI alone, I've worked on every part of the app.

Software Engineer, Google, London, UK - May 2011 - May 2014

I was Tech Lead of three APIs in Ads Product Area: The AdSense Management API, the AdSense Host API and the AdX Seller API. Whilst in this I role lobbied for the creation of AdSense for iPhone, learned the necessary skills to build it, and shipped it within two quarters.

Development Engineer, SeeByte - 2005 - May 2011

Responsible for prototyping and productisation of various projects related to autonomous underwater robotics. Acted as floating "fixer" engineer moving between projects as required. Including onsite work in: Aberdeen; The North Sea (on board the Subsea Viking); Reykjavik, Iceland; Baku, Azerbaijan; and Dampier, Western Australia.

Prototype Testing Engineer, ST Microelectronics, Edinburgh, UK – June 2003 - Aug 2003 Summer Job. Tested and verified camera chips for Nokia mobile phones. Classified and assisted in first stage diagnosis of faulty chips.

Innovation Engineer, Pryor Marking Technologies, Sheffield, UK - Sep 2000 - Oct 2001

Gap year placement. Designed and oversaw production of industrial marking equipment. Assisted with IT support and maintenance in engineering drawing office. Developed zero budget in house software solutions.

Education

Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh, UK - PhD,

Human Computer Interaction / Autonomous Underwater Robotics,

Graduated 2011

Thesis Title: "The design and implementation of a system for the automatic generation of narrative debriefs for AUV Missions"

The University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK – BSc (hons), Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science,

Graduated 2005

Honours project: "Control of an autonomous blimp."

Skills

Java, Objective-C, C++, C, Python, Ruby, Swift, JavaScript and Go to varying levels of proficiency. Familiarity, but not yet proficiency with functional programming languages and concepts. Comfortable with SQL, SPARQL and other similar query languages.

Programming at various levels of resource constraint: embedded, mobile, robotics, server, etc. Graphics programming. Mostly scene-graph based, but some OpenGL experience.

Most of my specific framework experience (outside of iOS) is very Google specific, however. Also have experience of video editing and CAD. Can pick up other skills as needed.

Personal Projects

- Currently Unnamed Chess Game. Nothing public yet, but happy to talk about it in person;
- Procedural Landscape Generation. A list of the blog posts I wrote on this can be found here: http://harveynick.com/2016/10/16/procedural-landscape-generation/

Hobbies and Interests

I love staying in shape, going to the cinema, reading, playing board games and travel.

References

Available on request.